One of the most powerful features of Android, since the
start of the platform has been the ability to deliver
timely notifications to users. We're going to add a simple
one to our weather app. This simple notification will show the
weather icon for the forecast, the forecast text, and the
high and low temperature for the day. One of the key
things we wanted to point out is how not to
be spammy with our notification. Our app will display at most
a single notification. It really wouldn't make sense if these
notifications stacked up anyhow. They don't display enough information to
give context. The key thing with notifications is to deliver
a useful morsel of information, formatted in a standard way, so
that it harmonizes with the rest of the system. We'll
start by adding a string for the preference for the
last time we sent a notification to the user. As
well as a format string for the body of the notification.
Let's implement the notification inside of our sync adapter.
Our notification will be based upon what is in
the database. So, we'll create projection and column indices
value in our sync adapter, for the weather id. Description,
max and then temperature, let's add a function to
notify us of the weather. We'll add some additional
constants up here. One for day in mili's and
one so that we an use the same notification ID.
Reusing the notification ID means that our application will only
post at most one notification. And then finally, we'll call
this function at a reasonable place within our on perform
sync function within our sync adapter. Inside of notify weather, we'll
check to see whether or not, we've actually shown notification
that day. If we haven't, then we'll talk to the database.
Get a cursor for the current resolver for the current
day, and then fetch the data, but one thing were not
doing is actually showing the notification. Now all right, were getting near
the end. Implement a weather notification,
build our notification using Notification Compat.builder
pointing to a Pending Intent built by the v4 compatible. TaskStackBuilder and
sent with the NotificationManager. Hint: an
explicit intent to our main activity is
a good idea here. There's lots of documentation on this you'll want to read.